Guide to the Janet G. Travell papers, 1910-1997 MS0704.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Janet G. Travell papers
1910-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Travell, Janet G.
MS0704.UA
55 Linear Feet
Collection includes correspondence, press releases, papers, case reports, data from experiments, lecture notes, booklets, articles, conference programs, anatomical drawings, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, and artifacts.
Acquisition Information
Papers were donated to the Gelman Library University Archives in 1998 by Dr. Travell's daughters, Virginia Powell Street and Janet Powell Pinci.
Historical or Biographical Note
Dr. Janet G. Travell (1901-97) served on the faculty of The George Washington University School of Medicine and University Hospital as Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine from 1961-70, Emeritus Clinical Professor of Medicine from 1970-88, and was made an Honorary Clinical Professor of Medicine in 1988. She remained an active figure up until her death at the age of ninety-five, writing, giving lectures, and attending conferences.
Dr. Travell was a distinguished member of the medical community, serving as personal physician to two United States Presidents: John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson (and the first woman to hold the post.) She was also renowned as an expert on myofascial pain - a term used to describe pain and dysfunction of skeletal muscles - and pioneered numerous techniques for dealing with chronic pain. Dr. Travell co-authored, with David G. Simons, M.D., the acclaimed two-volume textbook Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction. The Trigger Point Manual.
Janet Travell was born December 17, 1901 to Willard and Janet Davidson Travell. Her father was a practicing physician for over sixty years, and his enthusiasm for life and medicine influenced both Janet and her sister Virginia (Travell Weeks) to follow in his footsteps. Janet graduated Phi Beta Kappa from Wellesley College in 1922. In 1926 she earned her M.D. from Cornell University Medical College (New York City), receiving the John Metcalf Polk Memorial Award for the highest scholastic standing during her four years in medical school. Two years of internship and residency at New York Hospital followed, in which she simultaneously served as ambulance surgeon on the New York City police force. She was given the rank of Lieutenant, and described the period as "really fascinating and valuable" to her medical training.
Dr. Travell married John W.G. Powell, an investment counselor, in 1929. The marriage, which lasted until Mr. Powell's death in 1973, produced two daughters, Janet and Virginia. Following her residency at New York Hospital, Dr. Travell was a research fellow at Bellevue Hospital, studying the effect of digitalis in thousands of patients with lobar pneumonia. She then returned to Cornell and began work in the Department of Pharmacology as an Instructor and later as Associate Professor of Clinical Pharmacology. Before acquiring a special interest in muskuloskeletal pain, Dr. Travell was Consultant in Cardiology at Sea View Hospital in Staten Island, doing studies on chest pain.
It was during her time studying arterial diseases at Beth Israel Hospital in New York as a Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation fellow (1939-41) that Dr. Travell became absorbed in the problems of skeletal muscle pain. Dr. Travell helped develop new anesthetic techniques for treating painful muscle spasm by employing local procaine injection and vapocoolant sprays such as ethyl chloride (used widely in sports medicine today), and, starting in the mid-1950's, Flouri-Methane spray. It was this pioneering expertise that changed her life in more ways than one. In 1955 she was called upon by the orthopedic surgeon of then Senator John F. Kennedy, who had failed to recover from major back surgeries related to injuries he suffered in World War II. Dr. Travell was able to locate muscular sources for his chronic pain, and injected low-level procaine directly into the Senator's lumbar muscles, which proved effective. She also discovered that one of Kennedy's legs was shorter than the other, and ordered special shoes that would relieve the stress this condition put on his back. Without the medical expertise of Dr. Travell, Kennedy and his family were convinced that he would not have been able to further his political aspirations.
When John Kennedy was elected President in 1960, he appointed Dr. Travell to the post of Personal Physician to the President, because of his strong belief in her work. She advocated his use of a rocking chair to alleviate President Kennedy's back pain and in the process popularized their use among the public, who saw the President pictured in his rocker in the Oval Office. (Dr. Travell took aspects of seating design seriously, and worked as a consultant to such companies as John Deere and Lockheed to produce more comfortable and supportive seats for tractors and airplanes.) Dr. Travell would go on to serve President Lyndon Johnson after the death of President Kennedy, and left the White House in 1965.
Dr. Travell, who was appointed to the staff of The George Washington University School of Medicine and University Hospital as Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine shortly after coming to the White House, remained active teaching, writing, and giving lectures across the country. She was the author of more than 100 scientific articles and co-authored, with long-time colleague David G. Simons, M.D., the acclaimed two-volume book Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction. The Trigger Point Manual. In 1968, Dr. Travell published her autobiography, Office Hours: Day and Night. She said she wrote it for a number of reasons: to inform young people about the profession of medicine, to represent to parents and educators the life of a female physician, to present a philosophy of medicine and a way of life, and to record for history personal recollections of her years in the White House. In its pages one finds a woman of incredible physical and mental vitality.
The zeal Dr. Travell had for life was evident in her professional career as well. The pioneering techniques she developed for treating and controlling muscle pain were shared with other physicians as well as dentists, nurses, physical therapists, acupuncturists, massage therapists, chiropractors, followers of Kinesiology, and other members of the healthcare profession. The work of Dr. Travell allowed countless patients to benefit from her research and practice over the course of her life, and well beyond.
Dr. Travell died Aug. 1, 1997 of heart failure at the age of 95 at her home in Northampton, Massachusetts.
There is a memorial website created by Janet Travell's family. In Memory Of Janet Travell MD.
Collection Scope and Content
Material in this collection includes correspondence, press releases, papers, case reports, data from experiments, lecture notes, booklets, articles, conference programs, anatomical drawings, galley proofs of publications, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, and artifacts. This material ranges in date from 1910-1997.
The collection contains a wealth of information on the work of this medical pioneer, including research and lecture notes, papers, articles, conference reports, and correspondence with colleagues. It allows the researcher to see how medical theories and treatments have evolved over the course of fifty years. It is strong in addressing myofascial pain disorders, which Dr. Travell specialized in, as well as her role as White House physician.
The Janet G. Travell, M.D. papers were donated to the Gelman Library University Archives in 1998 by her daughters, Virginia Powell Street and Janet Powell Pinci. The collection is open to research, with the following proviso from the donors: "This collection is for research and study use only. Permission must be obtained from the donors for publication and/or any commercial use of the materials."
Collection Organization
Organized into seven series: Conferences, symposiums, and lectures; Papers, manuscripts, reports and subject research; Articles; Correspondence; White House Years; Galley Proofs and manuscript drafts of Dr. Travell's books; and Personal papers, books and certificates.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Myofascial pain syndromes; Medical care; Medicine; Washington (D.C.); Pain management; Presidents; White House (Washington, D.C.); Photographs; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald); George Washington University; George Washington University. School of Medicine; George Washington University. Hospital; Travell, Janet G.
- Conferences, symposiums, and lectures, 1946-1995; MS0704 Series 1; 8 Linear feet (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 16, Box 17, Box 4, Box 3, Box 6, Box 5, Box 14, Box 15, Box 2, Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of lecture notes, programs, itineraries, correspondence, and photographs. The material covers the years 1946-95. These materials all relate to conferences and symposiums Dr. Travell attended and participated in, and lectures she presented. Among some of the larger organizations represented are the North American Academy of Manipulative Medicine, New York Academy of Medicine, American Academy of Pain Management, American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine, Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, Walter Reed Army Medical Center, along with universities such University of Southern California, UCLA, University of Texas-Houston, Rice University, Indiana University, University of Maryland, and University of New Mexico.
  - Conferences, Lectures: 5th Annual Bernard Jankelson Memorial Lecture, 10/04/1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: 5th Cold Injury Conference, Ladd Air Force Base, AK, 03/10/1957 -03/15/1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: 6th Cold Injury Conference, Fort Knox, KY, 07/06/1958 -07/10/1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: 11th Annual Seminar on Diseases of the Temporomandibular Apparatus, Pasadena, CA, 04/24/1983 -04/27/1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: A.M.A. conference lecture on Groin Pain, San Francisco, 06/28/1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: A.M.A. Exhibit on Cardiac Pain, NY, NY, 06/01/1953 -06/05/1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Academy of General Practice conference, Atlantic City, NJ, 03/24/1952 -03/27/1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Academy of General Practice conference, Salt Lake City, 04/22/1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Academy of General Practice, Delaware Chapter lecture, 12/04/1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Advanced Myofascial Pain Workshop, Ft. Lauderdale, FL, 03/15/1997 -03/16/1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Air Force Area Medical Wives lecture, 03/05/1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Allan Memorial Institute of Psychiatry, Montreal, 03/16/1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Cranio-Mandibular Orthopedics, Atlanta, GA, 05/25/1978 -05/27/1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation conference, Boston, 10/21/1984 -10/26/1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Compensation Medicine lecture, 05/21/1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Craniomandibular Orthopedics meeting (dedicated to Dr. Travell), San Francisco, 05/24/1979 -05/26/1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Cranial Mandibular Disorders - transcript of Dr. Travell's presentation, Chicago, 05/21/1980 -05/24/1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Cranio-Mandibular Disorders meeting, Chicago, 05/21/1980 -05/24/1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Cranio-Mandibular Disorders, Chicago, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of General Practice, 03/24/1958 -03/27/1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of General Practice conference, Salt Lake City, UT, 04/22/1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Oral Medicine meeting, Baltimore, MD, 12/05/1986 -12/07/1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Orthapaedic Surgeons meeting, Virginia Beach, VA, 04/21/1988 -04/23/1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Osteopathy meeting, Colorado Springs, CO, 05/24/1973 -05/26/1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management meeting, Stockton, CA, 09/14/1990 -09/16/1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management meeting, Baltimore, MD, 08/29/1991 -09/01/1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management, Albuquerque, NM, 10/08/1992 -10/11/1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management conference, Knoxville, TN, 10/14/1993 -10/17/1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management conference, Knoxville, TN, 10/14/1993 -10/17/1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Pain Management, Dallas, TX, 09/14/1995 -09/17/1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Baltimore, MD, 10/19/1986 -10/24/1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Association for the Study of Headache meeting, Chicago, 06/25/1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Association for the Study of Medicine, Chicago, 06/20/1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Association of Endodonists - Women's Auxiliary meeting, Houston, Texas, 04/14/1977 -04/16/1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Association of Endodonists - Women's Auxiliary meeting, Houston, Texas, 04/14/1977 -04/16/1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Association of Orthodontists meeting, Washington, DC, 05/05/1990 -05/09/1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Back Society meeting, Chicago, 05/04/1990 -05/06/1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American College Obstetrics and Gynecologists conference, NY, NY, 10/14/1965 -10/16/1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American College of Clinical Pharmacology and Chemotherapy meeting, Philadelphia, 04/29/1966 -04/30/1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American College of Physicians conference, Kansas City, KS - Paper No. 1 "Skeletal Muscle Pain,", 03/23/1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American College of Physicians conference, Kansas City, KS - Paper No. 2, 03/23/1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Congress of Physical Medicine conference - Ethyl Chloride Spray, Denver, CO, 09/06/1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine, 1951-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine - Low Back Pain Lecture - Atlanta, 11/16/1975 -11/21/1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine, New Orleans conference, LA, 11/18/1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine conference, Washington, DC, 10/27/1991 -11/01/1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Dental Association conference - program, 11/10/1974 -11/14/1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Dental Association Symposium, 11/10/1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Equilibration Society Conferences, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Heart Association and New York Heart Association meeting, Atlantic City, NJ, 04/09/1953 -04/12/1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Medical Association Meeting, Exhibit on "Painless Injections," June, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Medical Association Scientific Exhibit on Myofascial Pain, Atlantic City, NJ, 06/11/1951 -06/15/1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Medical Association Scientific Exhibit on Somatic Pain, Atlantic City, NJ, 06/09/1947 -06/13/1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Medical Writers Association meeting., 10/16/1979 -10/20/1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Osteopathic Association-Bermuda Seminar, 10/10/1969 -10/12/1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Osteopathic Association-Bermuda Seminar, 10/10/1969 -10/12/1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Physical Therapy Association, Washington, DC, 06/30/1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Podiatry Association convention, Atlantic City, NJ, 04/29/1971 -05/02/1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Podiatry Association lecture, 04/30/1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Rheumatism Society meeting, 06/1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics meeting, 06/20/1970 -06/21/1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Society For Pharmacology & Experimental Therapy, New Haven, CT, 09/07/1953 -09/09/1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: American Society for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Charlottesville, 09/1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Annual Meeting of the Cranio-Facial Pain Center, Bethesda, MD, 10/19/1985 -10/22/1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Annual Symposium on Head, Face, and Neck Pain - Craniofacial Pain Center, Bethesda, MD, 10/15/1983 -10/19/1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Anthelmintics Lecture, Georgetown University, Washington, DC, 12/17/1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Arizona State Dental Association meeting lectures, 02/02/1971 -02/03/1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Arizona State Dental Association meeting lectures, 02/02/1971 -02/03/1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Arthritis Update seminar, Washington, DC, 12/05/1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Atlanta Press Club lecture, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Austin Riggs Center, Inc. seminar, Stockbridge, MA, 03/16/1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Baltimore Voice Study Group lecture - Pain and the Voice, 05/04/1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Basic concepts of vapocoolant spray (lecture notes), Washington, DC, 06/30/1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Bermuda Lectures, 10/10/1969 -10/12/1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Beth Israel Clinical Conference, New York, NY, 04/08/1952 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Bone lecture, 05/06/1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Brandeis University National Women's Committee talk, 04/23/1969 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: California Medical Association conference, Los Angeles, 03/09/1979 -03/14/1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Casualty Hospital (DC) Skeletal Muscle Pain lecture, 04/14/1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Celebration of Women in Medicine, Hahnemann University (Philadelphia), 03/06/1983 -03/10/1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Chicago Medical School Regional Physiatric Conference, 09/15/1984 -09/16/1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Chicago NAAM Council, 04/24/1970 -04/25/1970 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Chicago Symposium on Deep Pain Sensation, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Clifford Fox International Study Group, Buffalo, New York, 03/1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Conference on Rheumatology, Aix-les-Bains, France, 06/28/1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Connecticut Society of Physical and Rehabilitative Medicine, 05/01/1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Copies of Lantern Slides that are used for TMJ talks, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cornell Conferences on Therapy - Relief of Pain by ethyl chloride spray, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cornell Practitioners Conference - Sciatica and Low Back Pain, 1947 ca. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cornell University Women's Clubs, New York, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: County Medical Society, Philadelphia, 10/05/1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cranio-Fascial Pain Center symposium, 10/24/1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cranio-Fascial Pain Center seminar, 05/15/1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cranio-Fascial Pain Center symposium, Bethesda, MD, June, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Cranio-Fascial Pain Center seminar, 12/03/1992 -12/06/1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Dallas County Dental Society lecture, 03/12/1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Danbury Hospital (CT) lecture, 12/05/1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Dental Group lecture, 12/16/1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Dental Management interview and transcript, Cleveland, OH, 03/09/1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Dental Management meeting, 03/12/1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Dental Science Group of DC meeting, 12/03/1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Department of Veteran Affairs course on Myofascial Pain, NY, 12/08/1993 -12/11/1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: District of Columbia Dental Society meeting, 04/18/1978 -04/22/1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: District of Columbia Dental Society meeting, 04/16/1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: District of Columbia Medical Society Wives lecture, Mar.10, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: District of Columbia Rheumatism Lecture (with David Zohn), 11/18/1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: District of Columbia Women's Medical Society lecture, 03/05/1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Doctors Hospital Medical meetings of the month, 02/1975 -02/1976 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Eastern Dental Orthopedic Study Group, White Plains, NY, 06/13/1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Eastern Regional Osteopathic Convention, Kiamesha Lake, NY, 04/27/1972 -04/30/1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Exhibit "The Myofascial Genesis of Pain,", 1948 -10/1950 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Extra photo illustrations of slide used for lectures, 1950ca. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Federated Democratic Women of Ohio (Columbus) Lecture, 10/02/1971 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology conference, Atlantic City, NJ, 04/14/1962 -04/19/1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology meeting, Cleveland, OH, 04/29/1951 -05/03/1951 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Florida Academy of General Dentistry Myofascial Pain Seminar, 05/10/1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Florida Dental Association meeting, 05/22/1974 -05/24/1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Florida Society of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgeons meeting, Lake Buena Vista, Florida, 03/29/1985 -03/31/1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Focus on Pain, 03/06/1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Foundation for Orthodontic Research meeting, Palm Springs, CA, 04/13/1978 -04/15/1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)